PAKKAWAT KOMONMAN

PHONE: 084-342-6242 AGE: 33

EMAIL: <u>pakkawatko@gmail.com</u> EXPECTED SALARY: 40,000 (Negotiable)

ADDRESS: Phayathai Bangkok and Wangnoi Ayutthaya.

PROFILE

As a Process Engineer and Citizen Data Analyst who is passionate about Data Analytics. I've been leaning Data Science, Data Engineering and Data Analysis at Data Camp, YouTube, Kaggle by myself for over 1 years. Furthermore, I'm studying **ME in Big Data Engineering** at DPU. Although I'm newbie to data career, I'm confidence that I can deal with any tough jobs because my attitude is "**lifelong learning**". We can learn and find solution for free just google it. If I work at your company, I wish I could perform IS or Thesis about improving your business by Data Analytics.

EDUCATION

2021-Now Studying Master's Degrees in Big Data Engineering, Dhurakij Pundit University.

Compulsory Courses: Course Curriculum»

- 1st semester (Jul-Dec'21): Big Data Mining, Big Data Management and System Design (RDBMS, DWH, Hadoop, SQL, NoSQL), Programing (Python, R, SQL, Unix), Mathematics for Data Science.
- 2nd semester (Jan-May'22): Big Data Exploration and Preparation, Advanced Big Data Analytics, Cloud Computing and Container.
- Summer (Jun-Jul'22): Internet of Things, Business Intelligent.
- 2nd Year: Software Engineering for AI., IS/Thesis.

2007-2011 Bachelor's Degrees in Industrial Engineering, Kasetsart University.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCES

2017-Now Sr. Process Engineer and Data Analyst at Magnecomp Precision Technology. (Ayutthaya)

- •(2020-Now) Built Power BI reports about KPI, Ad hoc reports, ETL from data sources, designed visualization dashboard, created measure (DAX), finding insight through visualization for Process Engineering department.
- •Optimized input parameters for product output parameters by using classical statistic methods like Linear Regression, Correlation, ANOVA, t-test.
- Analyzed process performance by using Histogram, Boxplot, Scatter Plot, SPC.
- •Supported customer's issue like provided 8D reports and Failure Analysis (FMEA).

2015-2017 Ouality Assurance at Magnecomp Precision Technology. (Ayutthaya)

•Analyzing product parameters, alerted quality problem to manufacturing and provided QA outgoing shipment reports for customer.

2012-2015 <u>Customer Quality Engineer / Product Engineer at NMB-Minebea. (Ayutthaya)</u>

•Provided packages for new products, Failure Analysis, Leading a customer visit.

SKILLS

LANGUAGE: English. (Good with TOEIC = 710 in 2014)

PROGRAMMING: Python, R, SQL, Unix, Power Shell.

SOFTWARE: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Power BI, Tableau, Hadoop, Spark, Rapid Miner, H2O,

Amazon Web Service (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP), MS office & Power Query,

Minitab.

PROJECTS & CERTIFICATES

Please find my updated projects and certificates here: https://pakkawatk.github.io/portfolio/

